okay so most of the people who are gonna
be watching this video know what the
Dunbar number is because I've talked
about it before I want to talk about the
Dunbar number both as very arbitrary
that one of the characteristics or few
is that to me it's like the four-minute
mile one of the reasons we don't break
it is because we think we can't break it
and once we do many groups will be able
to break it but just like the
four-minute mile that doesn't mean all
of humanity is then able to break it
just the top groups the top people in
those groups but the more were able to
create the infrastructure to do that to
look at what are the constraints the
Dunbar number why does it exist and how
can we get beyond it because most Dunbar
groups are random in most traits but one
so you're born to a group of people but
you're genetics within that group your
personality type your argue are going to
be different and so you didn't choose
that and even if you do choose it if
it's like your workplace you still don't
choose the rest of what comes along with
it right who your workplace hires
outside of that so because it's a
randomized assortment of people I feel
like that's gonna naturally constrain
the number but what I want to talk about
is the relationship between the Dunbar
number and these other two numbers so
you can't have an effective team with
the Dunbar number you can't have a
hundred and fifty people having a
conversation or 150 people know what's
going on in a single project without it
being a broadcast project right with
like one or two people being the leaders
and telling everyone else what to do but
in an effective group you can actually
come to consensus you can have a
conversation where everyone as everyone
is heard and has a turn to speak and so
and then there's a larger number a
greater number that is everyone every
individual no matter how unique they are
how much of an outlier they are can
hopefully find their effective group of
people and also hopefully their Dunbar
group but you're really an outlier yt3
you know what
to nine other people might be here Holy
Grail
there's also of course the individual
the individual acts as a node in all of
them but especially in how many groups
they are part of in the effective number
and then what number are those teams of
are those effective teams all part of
the same Dunbar group or are they part
of multiple Dunbar groups the problem
multiple Dunbar groups our individual
nodes are what connect us to make the
Dunbar number greater to be able to
solve problems on the greater number
scale or between two thousand and ten
million people what kind of
infrastructure do we need in place to be
able to solve problems on that number on
that level to be able to effectively
create groups that are the Dunbar number
and effective teams that are the
effective number I don't know if I
explained that all well but I would love
to get together and talk about this
concept of how do we what is the Dunbar
number and why does it exist and how can
we possibly break it as well as in this
format of like what makes an effective
team what level of rules do you want on
each level right if you my guess is the
rules kind of exist on the Dunbar level
and then effective teams can can you
have some wiggle room on those rules but
they still have to follow the Dunbar
teams rules that they're a part of even
if there's a little bit of leeway and
the less rules that are in the greater
number level the better so that everyone
can form a Dunbar group that works for
them they can find it if they the
greater number is very stringent that's
already a constraint with people
involved right it's only going to be a
greater number of people who are willing
to follow those rules and so the less
rules on the greater number team yes
just that rules exist on don't run over
and then the more were able to create
the logistics the infrastructure to be
able to grow the Dunbar number to be
able to effectively work on the teams do
able to find the teams find the Dunbar
number the it changes all of these
and so I would like to get together and
talk about the Dunbar number so I will
create a doodle pool for people who want
to talk about this especially in the
game be space as we are beyond the
Dunbar number what does it look like to
be have a greater number to be able to
have people in teams how can we have a
non broadcast way of making decisions
within the confinements and like
logistical issues like time zones and
geography and different abilities and
challenges like how what could that look
like I have some ideas
I met the ideas so if you that interests
you and you want to have a bigger
conversation about the Dunbar number
this greater number and this effective
number please answer the dutiful thanks